<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching | James Rosenthal</title>
    <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:58:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jdrosent.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience Teaching and TAing</title>
      <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:58:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructor-of-record&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructor of Record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 417 - Modern Wireless Communications&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Winter Quarter 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-assistant&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching Assistant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 595 - Advanced Topics in Communications&amp;ndash;Cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Spring Quarter 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 393 - Advanced Technical Writing and Communication&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Winter Quarter 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 393 - Advanced Technical Writing and Communication&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Fall Quarter 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 393 - Advanced Technical Writing and Communication&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Spring Quarter 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 271 - Introduction to Digital Design&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Winter Quarter 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EE 271 - Introduction to Digital Design&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Washington, Fall Quarter 2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Reviews</title>
      <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:58:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/reviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provided below are a few highlights from course evaluations that I&#39;ve received as an instructor and TA.
&lt;em&gt;PDF copies of the evaluation reports are available upon request&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James answered every single question we asked with patience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James was incredibly helpful and thoughtful and contributed well to help me through the labs by being patient and understanding. He presented
problems in ways that allowed me to developed and work to find the answers on my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James especially worked really hard to encourage students to ask questions. He was patient and
always tried to find explanations that worked for the particular student. If he didn&#39;t know an answer, he would actually try to find it himself. I always felt
very comfortable coming to James for help on the labs or homework.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James did a great job giving real world examples to explain concepts. He found out that I liked aerospace applications and went an extra mile to
provide examples that related to space which was awesome!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James is very patient and friendly, making his contributions in lab section effective and fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James devoted a lot of time to helping students and always helped me out when I needed him.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you James! I had a great quarter with you, awesome TA :D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James is the best TA i’ve ever seen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James was very helpful and also very patient with helping us code. Debugging is super tenuous but James helped a lot with easing my mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James was very accessible and willing to help. Clearly knows his stuff.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James was the best TA I have ever had. He was helping everybody all the time. Every student knew they could go to him for help. He was always
willing to help and would stay in the labs for hours on end at times. There was a specific time when he stayed until midnight helping students. He&amp;hellip;would sometimes stay over their assigned office hour times and interfere with their own personal responsibilities just to help us out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He was available to help even at 10 at night&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James knows his content for the class , and with one peek he can find the problems for my labs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More TAs like James Rosenthal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More James&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James was able to teach us a extremely useful writing and presentation skills&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James is really helpful and cares student&#39;s performance. Thank you, James!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James did a really good job of reinforcing what we learned in lectures in his quiz sections.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James is a great communicator that gets his points across well. He understands students&amp;rsquo; questions and answers them in-depth and to the bests of
his ability. I wish he could have taught the whole course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for being a fantastic TA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Science Foundation&#39;s Research Experience for Teachers</title>
      <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/nsfret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 12:58:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/nsfret/</guid>
      <description>












&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Working together with Alexandra Pike to analyze recent measurement data. UW Campus Seattle, WA.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glowing Pickle Demo</title>
      <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/glowingpickle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 12:58:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/glowingpickle/</guid>
      <description>












&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;featured.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Speaking with the students. UW Campus Seattle, WA.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;pickle.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The &lt;em&gt;Glowing Pickle&lt;/em&gt; demo. UW Campus Seattle, WA.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;explain.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Discussing the science behind why the pickle glows (and why it smells so bad afterwards). UW Campus Seattle, WA.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HUNCH</title>
      <link>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/hunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 12:58:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdrosent.github.io/teaching/hunch/</guid>
      <description>












&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Students present their finished locker to a NASA HUNCH team member from Johnson Space Center in Houston. Newport News, VA.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The completed locker arriving to the International Space Station. Low Earth Orbit, Space.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
